A Guide to the Virginia Equal Rights Amendment Ratification Council papers, 1970-1982
Library of Virginia
- Series VII: Equal Rights Amendment, General information, 1978-1981., Extent: 1 box. (Box 13)
  - Unratified States ERA Coalitions, Utah. (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Women's Legislative Packet. (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Legislative Hearings. (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Legislative Session, 1979. (Box 13, Folder 34)
- Series VIII: Equal Rights Amendment, Issues, 1972-1980., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 14-16)
  - Abortion. (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Affirmative Action. (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
  - Constitution. (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
  - Court cases. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Credit. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Criminal laws and penal institutions. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Day care. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Democratic Party. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Discrimination complaints, etc. (Box 14, Folder 12-13)
  - Divorce. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Education. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - ERA effects, criminal law. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - ERA effects, education. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - ERA effects, family law. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - ERA effects, juries. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - ERA effects, juvenile law. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - ERA effects, marital property laws. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - ERA effects, prisons. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - ERA effects, religion. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Elections, 1977. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Employment. (Box 14, Folder 25-27)
  - Fears/arguments and opposition. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Federal power. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - General. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Grant projects. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Hatch Act. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Health and abuse. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Senate hearing, 22 March 1972. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Historical information- Feminist, 1980. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - History- Virginia, general. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Homemakers. (Box 15, Folder 10-12)
  - Inheritance. (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
  - Insurance. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Jury duty. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Labor. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Labor laws. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Legislation. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Media/newspapers. (Box 15, Folder 20-21)
  - News clippings. (Box 15, Folder 22-25)
  - Non-traditional jobs. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Other states. (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Press coverage. (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Privacy. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Property law. (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Publications. (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - Rape. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Ronald Reagan, 1972. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Referendum. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Rescission. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Right wing. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Rules change. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Senate Subcommittee. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Sexual preference. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Social Security. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Support obligations. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Women's groups. (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Series IX: Advertising and Publicity, 1962-1980., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 16-18)
  - Advertising, 1980. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Advertisement, Northern Virginia Daily, January 1978. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Advertisements, 1976. (Box 16, Folder 16-17)
  - Audio-visual materials. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - William B. Aycock, "The Great Common Toilet Scare." (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - ERA Impact on Black America. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Charlotte Bunch, "ERA Debate: A Tendency to Blame the Victims." (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Mary Callis, "Ratification of the Equal Rights Amendment." (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Cartoon, Washington Star, 1974. (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Christian Science Monitor reprints. (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Rev. Eldon Von Clemens. (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Common Cause (promotional, educational). (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - A Conservative for ERA. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Constituent Visit Guide, Virginia NOW. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Educational resources, locally developed. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - ERA Fact Sheet. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - ERAmerica. (Box 17, Folder 7-9)
  - Gala Kits. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Ellen Goodman and F.R.W.S. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Keesling report, History of the ERA to 23 March 1977. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Public Action Kits, League of Women Voters. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - The Leaguer, League of Women Voters. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - A Brief Support of Its Ratification, 1975, 1977. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Magazine articles, November 1979. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Media. (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
  - Minorities and Elenor Holmes Norton- Black America. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous ERA articles. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Mormons and ERA, publication, 1979, 1981. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - National Association of Women Lawyers (empty). (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - National American Women Suffrage Association (NAWSA). (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW). (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Petition for Ratification. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Quiz, rough draft. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Pennsylvania Governor Reports on ERA. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Photo negatives. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - The Press, contacts, editorials, releases, 1979-1981. (Box 18, Folder 14-18)
  - Public relations. (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Radio spots. (Box 18, Folder 20-21)
  - Marguerite Rawalt, article on women and property. (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Readers Digest, February 1977. (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Referenda. (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Richmond Newspapers Poll, 1976. (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Governor Charles S. Robb. (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Jill Ruckelshaus. (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Ruby H. Smith. (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Distinctions in Social Security. (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Surveys/petitions/forms. (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Kathryn F. Talley, "A Report on the ERA" (empty). (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Testimony, public hearing, 1978. (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Television, Virginia. (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Universities, Richmond Metropolitan Area. (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights. (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - VEA/NEA E.R.A. Emergency Action Kit. (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Vigil Philosophy- Friends Peace Committee, 1962. (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Lucille R. Williams, social work, mental health. (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Rev. Al. C. Winn, sermon. (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Womenfacts, NOW, Legal Defense and Education Fund. (Box 18, Folder 40)
- Series X: Newspaper clippings, 1970-1980., Extent: 1 box. (Box 19)
  - ERA in the Virginia [and other] Legislatures. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - ERA Supporters. (Box 19, Folder 2-3)
  - ERA Non-supporters, detractors. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Editorials, letters to the editor. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Cartoons. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Prominent Women, women in public service. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Women in the Work Force, Labor. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Other concerns to women. (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Series XI: Miscellaneous, 1981., Extent: 1 box. (Box 20)
  - Richmond Area ERA Ratification Council, General. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Richmond Area ERA Ratification Council, Finances. (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
  - E.R.A. Yes!, Correspondence. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - E.R.A. Yes!, Agendas. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - E.R.A. Yes!, Richmond Metropolitan Area. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - E.R.A. Yes!, Minutes,1981. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - E.R.A. Yes!, Membership. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Equal Rights Amendment Extension Hearings. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Commission on the Status of Women, report. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Final Cumulative Index of [General Assembly] Bills, etc., Volumes 2-3. (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Series XII: Maps, 1975-1982., Extent: 1 box. (Box 21)
  - House and Senate Districts, 1981-1982. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - E.R.A. Yes!, Richmond; Voting precincts map, 1975-1980. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Colonial Heights and Richmond area. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Fairfax County. (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Series XIII: Publications, 1975-1982., Extent: 3 boxes and oversize. (Box 22-24)
  - American Association of University Women (AAUW) ERA Ratification Task Force brochure. (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - American civil Liberties Union pamphlet. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - ACLU Women's Rights Projects brochures. (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organization (AFL/CIO), pamphlets and leaflets. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Board of Church and Society brochures. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - National Federation of Business and Professional Women, Inc. (BPW), booklets and pamphlets. (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Catholics Act for ERA, brochures. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Christian Science Monitor, reprint. (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Citizens' Advisory Council on the Status of Women, leaflets and booklets. (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Coalition of Women of Color Religious Committee for the ERA, leaflets. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Common Cause, leaflets and kits. (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Congressional Record, reprints. (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - ERA Lobby Office, cards. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - ERAmerica, booklets and pamphlets. (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - ERA Project (Falls Church, Va.), leaflets. (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - E.R.A. Yes! (Richmond, Va.), leaflets. (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - FOR ERA and League of Women Voters (Oakland, Ca.), leaflets and postcards. (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - General Assembly of Virginia, Senate Document No. 25 and explanatory material. (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Homemakers for ERA (HERA), brochures. (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
  - Interfaith Task Group of the ERA, Virginia Council of Churches, brochures. (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - League of Women Voters of the U.S., brochures. (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Labor for Equal Rights Now (LERN), booklets and forms. (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - National American Women Suffrage Association, leaflet. (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW), leaflets and brochures. (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - NOW Minority Women's Committee, brochures. (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - NOW- Virginia, booklets. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - National Women's Committee, brochures. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - North Carolinians United for ERA, booklet. (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Religious Committee for the ERA (RCERA), leaflets. (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Republican National Committee; and Democratic National Committee, Office of Women's Activities, leaflets. (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Richmond News-Leader, reprints. (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Richmond Times Dispatch, reprints. (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - United Methodist ERA Support Project, brochures. (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - U.S. Civil Service Commission, booklets. (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Virginia Council of Churches, letters. (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Education Association (VEA/NEA), pamphlets. (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Virginia E.R.A. Ratification Council, leaflets. (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Virginia Religious Coalition for the E.R.A., leaflet. (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - The Washington Post, reprint. (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Women's Equity Action League, leaflet. (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - YMCA of Richmond and American Association of University Women Virginia Division, program brochure. (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Other publications from unidentified or unspecified groups, booklets and leaflets. (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Oversized and non-published items. (Box 24)
    Posters, t-shirt, and pennants
  - Vigil Line posters. (Oversize on shelf)